

Madhuvaran Dussa

React Developer



Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Front-end Developer with 6 years of experience in designing, developing, and managing complex e-commerce sites, travel domain applications, banking applications and Internal Frameworks. Specialized in React, Redux, TypeScript, JavaScript, Angular, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, Express, Python.





+91 9121771397

vrnsr2884@gmail.com

Education

2011 - 2015

Auroras Engineering College (Affiliated to JNTU, Hyderabad)

Electronics And Communications

1999 - 2009

Shanthinikethan high school

High School

Work Experience

Senior React Developer • EPAM Systems





CBPAS is a Clinical Business Process Automation Solution, which is a Medical Domain Application that provides Automatic Solutions to Database By Writing Domain Configurations as well as Rule Configuration to Execute on top of a Cloud Database. It's a scalable application for use over multiple medical domain databases or different hospital databases to automate daily driven tasks and flow, such as Generating Alerts on behalf of patients, creating Patient Reports and collecting Data of particular Subjects Etc.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Develop a responsive web design using JavaScript, CSS, with libraries such as jQuery, and frameworks such as Material UI.
- Ability to create Reusable Components that can be utilized throughout the Application
- User Authentication Modules & Role Based Rendering and JWT Token Authorization.
- Domain & Rule Configuration Modules For Automatic Solutions.

Software Developer • Cognizant Technology Solutions



May 2019 - May 2020

Client On Boarding is an Application to provide access for bank employees to Create Customer Profile and Collecting Onboarding Requirement Details, Creating Relationships for Nomination and Extra Activities, as well as Benefit Schemes and joint account Etc. This Application We built for **Bank**Of Switzerland

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Ability to create Reusable Components that can be utilized throughout the Application
- Form Validations and Handling Dynamic Validations for Form using Yup
- Creating Form Using Formik, Yup
- Creating a Form Building Engine By Passing JSON Data to it.

Software Developer • Tata Consultancy Services

tcs

September 2018 - May 2019

Travelport is an Application Developed in the Travel Domain For Airlines. Application Provides a possible way to select seats and book a journey to your destination by Selecting Appropriate Flights. Here we were using Galileo's Server to fetch PNR Data and Flight Information.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Developed react web widgets and next generation dot com product for online booking of air tickets
- Responsible for React UI components
- Retrieving PNR based on Airline search and display in UI using React components.
- Sliced down epics into doable user stories and derived inter-team dependencies

Software Associate • AJR Info Systems Pvt Ltd



December 2015 - July 2018

AJR Info Systems Pvt Ltd is a product-based company which is developing its product named **SCOCU**, which stands for Scalable Configurable and Customizable application. SCOCU is a web application tool, using which we can develop any web application with minimal coding and with rapid development. It maintains all the database tables required for the application.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Working as a team member and responsible for Client Side scripting using Angular
- Creating Application forms based on the client requirements.
- Validating the user data using Angular Validations.
- Migrated Entire Application from Angular to React.

Skills Technology Library Language • React, Hooks Redux English Javascript • Redux-saga, Redux-thunk Hindi TypeScript Mobx React lite Telugu NodeJS ChartJS Express • Formik, Yup Html5 Material UI • react-i18next

- ES6
- JEST

Powered by CakeResume